[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：让我们进入面向对象的编程，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Let's get into an object oriented programming,
你怎么说？
what do you say?
所以当Brendan Eich设计JavaScript时
So when Brendan Eich designed JavaScript,
他受到一篇他读到的关于自我项目的论文的强烈影响。
he was very strongly influenced by a paper that he read about the self project.
而自己的项目是进入原型，而不是进入类。
And the self project was into prototypes not into classes.
他想，哇，这真是太棒了。
And he thought, wow that's pretty neat.
所以他决定用他的语言表达，但他并不完全理解
So he decided to put that in his language but he didn't fully understand it or
对此有信心。
have confidence in it.
所以他想出了某种打算
So he came up with something kind of intended to
更经典的想法是古典的人会更喜欢它。
be more classical thinking that the classical guys would like it better.
因此，这就是您应该如何使用JavaScript的最初预期模型。
So this is the original intended model for how you were supposed to use JavaScript.
所以我们要做个Gizmo
So we're gonna make a Gizmo.
这是我们的Gizmo构造函数。
That's our Gizmo constructor function.
我们将传入一个ID并创建一个属性
We'll pass in an ID and we'll create a property
对象的，即名为ID的对象，它将获得该值。
of the object with an, that is named ID, which will get that value.
我们希望我们的Gizmo继承t0String方法。
And we want our gizmos to inherit a t0String method.
因此，您这样做的方式是使用gizmo.prototype.toString=函数。
So the way you do that is use a gizmo.prototype.toString = function.
在该函数中实现toString方法。
In that function implements the toString method.
Java程序员看着这个说，该死的那是什么，
And the Java programmers looked at this and said, what the hell is that,
我的意思是这看起来很糟糕，这是什么.原型废话？
I mean this is awful looking that what's this .prototype crap?
为什么你泄露了你的东西，什么都没有，对吧？
Why you leaking your stuff and nothing's contained in anything, right?
你想让你的类有一些完整性，就像它被包裹在什么东西里一样。
You want to have your class have some integrity, like it's wrapped in something.
它的内脏溅得到处都是。
And this has its guts spilled all over the place.
这真是太可怕了。
This is just really awful.
但这就是Brendan认为语言将起作用的方式。
But this is how Brendan thought the language was going to work.
所以让我给你画个图，这样你就可以看到到底发生了什么。
So let me diagram this for you, so you can see what's actually going on.
这就是代码，
So this is that code,
放在屏幕上，新的Gizmo就是我们制作实例的方式。
put up on the screen, new gizmo is how we make the instance.
这是Gizmo的实例，
So this is the instance of the gizmo,
我们看到构造函数放入其中的ID属性。
we see the ID property that the constructor put in it.
这是Gizmo函数，因为在这种语言中函数是对象，
This is the gizmo function because in this language functions are objects,
所以它们也可以有属性。
so they can also have properties.
每个函数都有一个原型属性，
Every function is born with a prototype property,
以防万一它将被用作方法或构造函数。
just in case it's going to be used as a method or as a constructor.
而gizmo.prototype就是这个对象。
And the gizmo.prototype is this object.
这是gizmo.prototype，它包含这些字段。
This is gizmo.prototype and it contains these fields.
这是我们在那里分配的toString方法。
This is the toString method that we assign there.
并且系统还具有目标函数，即所有对象的构造函数
And the system also has the object function that's the constructor of all
对象。
objects.
我们已经讨论过对象原型，
And we've already talked about object.prototype,
这是所有对象文字都继承的东西。
that's the thing that all object literals inherit from.
所以我们可以在这里添加一个构造函数链接。
So we can add a constructor link here.
构造函数属性包含对构造函数的引用，因此
The constructor property contains a reference to the constructor, so
构造函数是gizmo。
gizmo.prototype.constructor is gizmo.
并且类似的object.prototype.structor是Object。
And similarly object.prototype.constructor is object.
你甚至可以绕过那个循环
You can even go around that loop as many
时间如你所愿，&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：但是
times as you want, &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: But
重要的是委托链接，继承链接。
the important thing is the delegation link, the inheritance link.
因此我们的实例继承了gizmo.prototype和
So our instance inherits from gizmo.prototype and
type继承自object.prototype。
gizmo.prototype inherts from object.prototype.
因此，如果我要求我的实例提供一个ID，我们在这里找到它，我们返回字符串。
So if I ask my instance for an ID, ID we find it here, we return the string.
如果我问我的实例它的Toos方法，它会说我没有Toos方法，
If I ask my instance for it's tooS method, it goes I don't have one,
他有一个，所以我们返回这个函数，就像它是这个对象的一部分一样。
he's got one so we return this function as though It were part of this object.
如果我们要他的Foo财产，他没有，
And if we ask for its foo property, he doesn't have one,
他没有，这是不确定的，好吗？
he doesn't have one, he doesn't have one, It's undefined, okay?
这就是Brendan认为你会使用这种语言的方式。
So that's how Brendan thought you're going to use this language.
这里有一些很好的想法，但是有点混乱，但是
And there are some good ideas in here, but it's kind of a mess but
您已经对JavaScript现在实际做的事情有了一些了解。
you got some idea about what JavaScript is actually doing now.
所以新的前缀，如果它是作为一个方法实现的，而不是
So the new prefix, if it had been implemented as a method instead of
作为运营商，这就是它应该做的。
as an operator, this is what it would do.
它将创建一个新对象，
It would create a new object,
它继承自functions.prototype属性。
which inherits from the functions.prototype property.
然后它将调用传入该对象的方法，将其绑定到这个，
And it will then call the method passing in that object, binding it to this,
得到一个结果，这个结果可能就是会得到的结果。
and getting a result and that result is probably what's gonna get returned.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：再一次，这是一种混乱，所以。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: And again, this is kind of a mess, so.
但我们还没有继承太多，所以
But we haven't inherited much yet, so
让我们重新审视这个关于继承的想法。
let's reexamine this thinking about inheritance.
所以如果我们替换原始原型对象，
So if we replace the original prototype object,
然后我们可以继承另一个对象的东西。
we can then inherit another object's stuff.
所以这毫无意义。
So that made no sense.
让我们来看一个例子，试着弄清楚这一点。
So let's look at an example try to figure this out.
所以我们要做一个Hoozit是从Gizmo继承的东西，
So we're going to make a Hoozit a Hoozit is something that will inherit from Gizmo,
好吗？
okay?
所以我们有一个像以前一样的Hoozit构造函数。
So we've got a Hoozit constructor like before.
我们将用Gizmo实例替换hoozit.prototype
And we're gonna replace hoozit.prototype with an instance of Gizmo
然后我们将添加一个额外的方法。
and then we'll add an additional method.
我们将在我们的新原型中添加一种测试方法。
We're gonna add a test method to our new prototype.
Java人看着这个说，该死的那是什么？
And the Java guys looked at this and said what the hell is that?
我的意思是我们认为另一个是坏的，但我的天哪，
I mean we thought the other one was bad, but holy cow,
这就是你写扩展的方式。
that's how you write extends.
你是认真的吗？
Are you serious?
这是，这是可怕的，这是绝对可怕的。
This is just, this is horrible and this is absolutely horrible.
所以让我们把它画出来，让我们看看这里到底发生了什么。
So let's diagram it, let's look at what's actually going on here.
这是我们的Hoozit实例。
So here's our instance of Hoozit.
这是我们之前在Gizmo.prototype中使用的Gizmo函数。
This is the Gizmo function that we had before in Gizmo.prototype.
这是我们在Hoozit.Prototype中的Hoozit函数。
And it was our Hoozit function in Hoozit.prototype.
但是我们用Gizmo的这个新实例替换Hoozit.prototype。
But we replace Hoozit.prototype with this new instance of Gizmo.
所以当我们添加委托链接时。
So when we add the delegation links.
我们从那个继承来的，
We've got that inheriting from that, which inherits from that,
这将从object.prototype继承，但我遗漏了这一点。
and that will inherit from object.prototype, but I left that one out.
因此，如果我们要求我们的新实例提供它的ID，我们就会在那里得到它。
So if we ask our new instance for its ID, we get it there.
如果我们要求它的测试方法，不，它在那里，我们将返回该方法。
If we ask for its test method, no, there it is, we'll return that method.
如果我们要求它的toString方法，去不，它在那里，我们会返回那个方法。
If we ask for it's toString method, go no, no, there it is, we'll return that one.
如果我们问它的构造函数属性，我们会说，不，是的。
If we ask for it's constructor property, we'll go, no, no, yes.
除了它是一个小玩意，哦，&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：那么我
Except it's a gizmo, oops, &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So which I
认为并不是那么糟糕，因为你永远不应该问它继承自什么。
think is not that bad because you should never ask anything what it inherits from.
你应该只问你能做什么
You should only be asking what can you do and
我们应该根据内容的性质来判断我们的对象。
we should judge our objects by the character of the contents.
所以，再一次，这就是它的工作原理。
So again, it's, that's how it works.
令人困惑的一个原因是有时我们
And one source of confusion is that sometimes we
将其视为原型链接。
consider this to be the prototype link.
但这个也叫.Prototype。
But this one is also called .prototype.
所以有两个指针，被指定为原型指针，
So having two pointers, which are designated as the prototype pointer,
这是完全不同的。
which are completely different.
而DISTINCT当然也是混淆的来源。
And distinct is certainly a source of confusion as well.
但大多数编写JavaScript的人都是这样使用的
But this is how most of the people who are writing the JavaScript are using
语言。
the language.
他们这样做，他们很痛苦，他们憎恨自己的生活。
They are doing this and they are miserable, they are hating their lives.
他们憎恨JavaScript，他们愤怒而痛苦。
And they are hating JavaScript and they're angry and bitter.
并希望他们最喜欢的语言做得更好，因为为什么
And wishing that their favorite language was doing better because why
他们有没有上过JavaScript写作课？
have they come to this writing classes in JavaScript.
太可怕了。
It's just awful.
所以是的，所以把它们放在一起，
So yeah, so putting them together,
只是这里有可怕的东西。
it's just there's awful stuff here.
只有丑陋的头部和缺乏抚慰的句法。
There is just the head of ugliness and in the lack of soothing syntax.
我们没有得到足够的代码重用。
We're not getting enough code reuse.
例如，两个构造函数都创建了一个ID属性，但是
For example, both constructors create an ID property, but
他们都必须重复这一点，而且这不是代码重用。
they both have to repeat that and that it's not code reuse.
所以世界上有很多的JavaScript库。
So there are lots and lots of JavaScript libraries in the world.
他们中的大多数人都认识到这里严重缺乏一些东西。
And most of them recognize that there is something seriously lacking here.
所以他们会提供一些机制
And so they'll provide some mechanism for
给这种经典的系统涂上糖衣，让它变得更好一点。
sugarcoating this sort of classical system in order to make it a little bit nicer.
例如，他们可能会创建一个名为new_structor的函数。
For example, they might do something like create a function called new_constructor.
它将构造函数。
And it will make constructor functions.
我会把我想要继承的东西传给它。
And I will pass into it the thing that I want to inherit from.
所以我想扩展对象，我想扩展Gizmo。
So I want to extend object, I want to extend gizmo.
我将传入一个构造函数，然后传入
And I'll pass in a constructor function and I'll pass in
包含我希望实例继承的方法的对象。
an object containing the methods that I want the instances to inherit.
所以它看起来不像Java，但至少您可以识别组件，对吗？
So it doesn't look like Java, but at least you can recognize the components, right?
所以这件事有更好的一面。
And so there is something nicer about this.
这个函数令人惊讶的是
And the surprising thing about this function
这就是整个功能。
is that that's the entire function.
所以JavaScript是一种非常有表现力的语言，
So JavaScript is such an amazingly expressive language,
如此强大的语言。
such a powerful language.
一小段代码就可以从根本上改变
That one little piece of code can radically transform
语言的出现，这是非常不寻常的，
the appearance of the language, which is pretty extraordinary,
不是很多语言都能做到这一点。
not a lot of languages can do that.
我推荐这种方法吗？
Do I recommend this approach?
不，我没有，尽管这显然比使用语言作为
No I don't, Even though this is clearly better than using the language as
本意是，你仍然被困在这个经典的范例中。
intended, you're still stuck in this classical paradigm.
除了你试图用一种语言进行经典编程
Except you're trying to do classical programming in a language
没有类型系统。
without a type system.
这真的很难。
And that is really really hard.
是的，课程提供了很多脆性。
Yeah, that classes provide a lot of brittleness.
如果没有持续的类型检查来保持你的诚实，
And without the constant type checking to keep you honest,
事情真的很容易变坏。
it's really easy for things to go bad.
而在JavaScript中，事情总是变得非常快。
And in JavaScript, things go bad very quickly all the time.
这就是为什么人们试图用JavaScript编写这个模型，
And that's why people who are trying to write in this model, in JavaScript,
对语言很生气。
are so angry at the language.
他们总是在愤怒的感觉中。
They're constantly in a sense of rage.